Benjamin B. Dally

benjaminda@gmail.com
530.761.3292
github.com/benjamindally
benjamindally.github.io/Portfolio/
linkedin.com/in/dallybenjamin/

Professional Summary

Innovative web developer with 4 years freelance experience in website design, development, and deployment. Seeking to break into technology sector full-time and migrate 7+ years experience managing, developing, and executing projects as an educator.

Technical Skills

Front End: React, Javascript, ES6, HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS+, RESTful API, jQuery, Bootstrap, Wordpress, Material-UI, UI/UX Focused Programming

Back End: MySQL, MongoDB, BCrypt Encryption, JSON Web Tokens (JWT), Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Mongoose, Virtual Private Server

Workflow: Model-View-Controller (MVC), Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object-Oriented Programming, Git (Git Hub, Git Bash, Git Lab)

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator, GIMP, Noun Project, MS Office

Professional Experience

Freelance Web Developer

Woodland, CA 2014-2018

Front End Developer

• Designed and developed sites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and Bootstrap

- Created professional designs for a variety of organizations, professionals and individuals
- Paid and unpaid clients, including musician Megan Kraft (<u>megankraft.com</u>), politician Shelley Dally (<u>shelleydally.com</u>), and self <u>cconlinejournal.org/fall14/digitalbridge/Home.html</u>

Woodland High School Classroom Teacher

Woodland, CA

2016-2018

- Established newspaper online through Wordpress and in print utilizing Adobe InDesign (whsorangepeel.com)
- Managed over 50 concurrent projects and provided feedback/evaluation for each
- Converted English curriculum to digital platform using Chromebooks, Google Classroom, web-based projects, iOS apps, etc.

Sacramento Job Corps Center

Sacramento, CA

2011-2014

Adult Education

- Mentored student's academic and psychological growth
- Achieved over 85% success rate of student GED completion within three months
- Overhauled curriculum to maximize student time, effort, and ability

Applications/Projects

Hambre May 2018

- Full stack web app that helps people find food trucks. Currently available in beta on Chrome Browser
- Personally responsible for React, MongoDB, API, BCrypt Encryption, JSON Web Tokens, Material-UI, Node, Deployment, MVC, Git

hambre-sacramento.herokuapp.com

Delta 32 March 2018

- Full stack project that helps easily connect users to medically and health related videos.
- Personally collaborated on MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap, API, jQuery, Javascript, HTLM5, and CSS.

<u>delta32.herokuapp.com</u> <u>github.com/DanFeinstat/delta32</u>

MERN New York Times Searcher and Saver (MERN NASS) Individual Project

June 2018

• Incorporated front and back end technologies to create an app that searches the NYT API for relevant articles, displays them using React, and allows the user to save them using MongoDB. github.com/benjamindally/mern-nyt-article-viewer mern-nyt-article-search-save.herokuapp.com/

Education

University of Davis Extension, Sacramento, CA Full Stack Developer Boot Camp 2018

California State University, Sacramento, CA Master of Arts: English (Composition and Rhetoric) 2014

GPA: 3.75

Created the site and published Master's Thesis in online journal cconlinejournal.org/fall14/digitalbridge/Home.html